A Finding Aid to the Maryette Charlton papers, circa 1890-2013, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Professional and Project Files, 1923-1998; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; 7.6 Linear feet Boxes 34-41, 81, OV 87
  - University of Iowa Museum of Art, 1954-1998; 6.1; Archival Resource Key
    - Correspondence, Archival Resource Key (Box 34)
      - Kujawski, Mary H., 1988-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 3)
      - Martin, Jeff, 1986-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 4)
      - Muhlert, Jan, 1975-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 5)
      - Pearson, Andrea G., 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 6)
      - Prokopoff, Stephen, 1992-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 7)
      - Wilke, Ulfert, 1970-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Maryette Charlton Collection, Archival Resource Key (Box 34)
      - Information and Notes, 1984-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 9)
      - Collection Inventory, 1986-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 10)
      - Art Appraisals, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 11)
      - Gift of Artworks, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 12-14)
      - Object Records for Collection Artwork, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 15)
      - Photographs of Artwork, 1986-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 16-17)
    - Elliott Collection, Archival Resource Key (Box 34)
      - Correspondence with Leone and Owen Elliott, 1962-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 18-21)
    - Elliott Collection, Archival Resource Key (Box 35)
      - Correspondence with Leone and Owen Elliott, 1996-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 35, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence about Elliott Estate Auction, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 35, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence, B, 1991-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 35, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence, C-D, 1992-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 35, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence, F, 1989-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 35, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence, G, 1992-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 35, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence, L-M, 1990-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 35, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence, S-V, 1990-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 35, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence, W-Y, 1991-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 35, Folder 9)
      - Notes on Phone Calls With Leone Elliott, 1983-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 35, Folder 10)
      - Notes on Phone Calls About Leone Elliott, 1991-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 35, Folder 11)
      - Leone Elliott's 100th Birthday, 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 35, Folder 12-13)
      - Leone Elliott Birthday Party, 1985 October 31; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 35, Folder 14)
      - Leone Elliott and Maryette Charlton Conversations, 1992-1994; Archival Resource Key; 10 Sound cassettes (microcassette); 6 Sound cassettes (Box 35, Folder 15)
        Informal interviews and conversations recorded on various dates at different locations.
      - Leone Elliott Obituary, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 35, Folder 16)
    - Elliott Collection, Archival Resource Key (Box 36)
      - Exhibition Catalogs, 1969-circa 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 36, Folder 1-2)
      - Printed Material, 1954-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 36, Folder 3-4)
        Oversized material housed in OV 87.
      - Photographs of Leone and Owen Elliott, 1964-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - Photographs of Leone Elliott, 1990-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 36, Folder 6-8)
    - Annual Reports, 1982-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 36, Folder 9-14)
    - Bulletins, 1976-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - Events Calendars, 1994-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 36, Folder 16)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1970-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 36, Folder 17-18)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Postcards, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Clipping about 25th Anniversary of Museum, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Printed Material on Annual Giving, 1972-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Printed Material on "Art History", 1985-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Printed Material on Des Moines Art Center, 1973-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Printed Material, 1964-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 37, Folder 7-9)
    - Oversized Calendar from Box 36, Folder 3, 1969-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box OV 87)
  - Other Professional and Project Files, 1923-1995; 6.2; Archival Resource Key
    Other professional and project files document Charlton's work and projects in Chicago and New York City. There are files on projects, grant applications, fellowships, conferences, committees, and membership records. Some of the most voluminous files are on Charlton's work at the Chicago Public School Art Society, as a color analyst at the Container Corporation of America, and as executor of artist Louise Medbery von Brockdorff's estate. This subseries also documents Charlton's affiliations with museums and universities. Information on storing and purchasing film equipment, mailing lists, festivals, and film ideas unrelated to specific film projects are found here as well. Additionally, there are files related to her film Zen in Ryoko-In.
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - 16mm Distribution Conference, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - 16mm Film Center Plans, 1965-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Acme News Pictures Printing Plates, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - American Film Institute Grant Application, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - Ampex Museum of Magnetic Recording, 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - Charlton Films Incorporation, 1960-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 37, Folder 15)
    - Chicago Public School Art Society, 1950-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 37, Folder 16-18)
    - Chicago Public School Art Society - Student Drawings, 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 37, Folder 19)
    - Chicago Public School Art Society - Public School Division Report, 1951-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 37, Folder 20)
    - Chicago Service Men Center, 1943-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 37, Folder 21)
    - Cinema Femina, 1973-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 37, Folder 22)
    - Collective for Living Cinema, Archival Resource Key (Box 37)
      - General Correspondence, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 37, Folder 23)
      - Correspondence about Event Attendance, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 37, Folder 24)
      - Publicity, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 37, Folder 25)
    - Collective for Living Cinema - Post Card Design, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Color Service Company, 1959-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Container Corporation of America, Archival Resource Key (Box 38)
      - General Correspondence, 1945-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - Egbert Jacobson Correspondence, 1946-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 38, Folder 4)
        Includes a copy of the book Basic Color
      - Color Charts and Notes, 1945-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 38, Folder 5)
      - Color Theory Charts and Articles, 1945-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 38, Folder 6)
        Oversized material housed in Box 81.
      - Project Notes, 1947-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 38, Folder 7)
      - Ostwald Color System, 1944-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 38, Folder 8)
      - Walt Disney Slotties Game, circa 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 38, Folder 9)
      - Printed Material on Color Theory, 1944-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - "Dance-Video Workshop" at Merce Cunningham Studio, 1984-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Film Budgets, 1965-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Film Budgets, Contacts, Credits and Copyrights, 1960-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - Film Editing Equipment, 1953-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 38, Folder 14)
    - Film Fundraising Ideas, 1958-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 38, Folder 15)
    - Film Ideas, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 38, Folder 16)
    - Film Lighting Equipment, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 38, Folder 17)
    - Film Mailing Lists and Locations for Previews, 1960-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 38, Folder 18)
    - Film Notes on Filmmaking, 1957-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 38, Folder 19)
    - Film Projectors, Screens, and Sound Equipment, 1957-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 38, Folder 20)
    - Film Projectors, Screens, and Sound Equipment, 1957-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Film Reviewing, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Film Screenings and Events, 1976-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Film Storage, 1964-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Film-Maker's Cooperative, 1981-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Filmstrips, 1952-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Filmtronics Labs, Inc., circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Foundations for Grants, 1960-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 39, Folder 8-9)
    - Guggenheim Foundation, 1957-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 39, Folder 10-12)
    - Harvard Theater Collection, 1987-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - Hull House, 1948-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 39, Folder 14)
    - Inter Society Color Council, 1945-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 39, Folder 15-18)
    - Louise Medbery von Brockdorff Estate, Archival Resource Key (Box 40)
      - Acquisition, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, 1964-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 40, Folder 2-6)
      - Legal Records, 1973-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 40, Folder 7)
      - Memorial Service, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Marshall Field and Co. Interior Design Department, 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 41, Folder 1-2)
    - Museum of Modern Art, New York, 1952-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - National Tribute to Alexander Calder Planning Committee, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 41, Folder 4-6)
    - Orchestra of Our Time, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Radcliffe Institute Fellowships, 1968-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Ragdale Foundation, 1985-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Schooley's Mountain, 1989-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - Women's Independent Film Exchange, 1977-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - YMCA, 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - Zen in Ryoko-In Screening, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - Zen in Ryoko-In Poetry Project Screening, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - Oversized The Color Helm Chart from Box 38, Folder 6, 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 81)
    - Oversized Container Corporation State Charts from Box 38, Folder 10, circa 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 81)
- Artist Research Files, 1949-circa 2000; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; 1.8 Linear feet Boxes 41-43, FCs 88-89
  Found here are general research files on artists which interested Maryette Charlton. Files contain mostly printed material such as books, articles, and clippings. Notable artists include Alexander Calder, Louise Nevelson, Kiki Smith, and Toshiko Takaezu. The series also includes autographed books, and typescript drafts by James Purdy, a writer who had a close working relationship with Maryette Charlton and Lillian Kiesler. There is also 1 film reel labeled "Calder" along with 1 copy print of the original reel.
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  - Abboud, Chafik, circa 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 41, Folder 15)
  - Berdich, Vera, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 41, Folder 16)
  - Blanc, Maurice, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 41, Folder 17)
  - Bourgeois, Louise, 1991-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 41, Folder 18)
  - Breer, Robert, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 41, Folder 19)
  - Calder, Alexander, 1965-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 41, Folder 20)
  - "Calder", circa 1980-circa 1990; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel Super 8 mm; 1 Film reel Copy print of original film reel Super 8 mm (Box 41, Folder 21-22)
    Motion picture film stored separately in film cans numbered FC 88-89
  - Candido, Tony, 1991-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 41, Folder 23)
  - Choucair, Saloua Raouda, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 41, Folder 24)
  - "Cindy the Glassblower", 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 41, Folder 25)
  - Dlugoszewski, Lucia, 1986-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 41, Folder 26)
  - Douglas, Scott, 1966-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 41, Folder 27)
  - Gruse, Elizabeth, 1949-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 41, Folder 28)
  - Herbert, F. John and Mel Aldringa, 1992-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 41, Folder 29)
  - Hirschfeld, Al, 1985-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 41, Folder 30)
  - Indiana, Robert, 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 41, Folder 31)
  - Kawai, Kanjiro, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 41, Folder 32)
  - Kelly, Ellsworth, 1986-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 41, Folder 33)
  - Kiang, Jackie, circa 1980-circa 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 41, Folder 34)
  - Lionni, Leo, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 41, Folder 35)
  - Melton, Hollis, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 41, Folder 36)
  - Miro, Joan, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 41, Folder 37)
  - Mueller, George, 1976-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 41, Folder 38)
  - Nevelson, Louise - Research Files, 1983-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 41, Folder 39)
  - Nevelson, Louise, Archival Resource Key (Box 42)
    - Dawns + Dusks, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 42, Folder 1)
      Book includes photographs by Maryette Charlton
    - Louise Nevelson: Aubes et Crepuscules, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Louise Nevelson, 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Printed Material, 1967-circa 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Newlin, Jeanne, 1995-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Paepcke, Elizabeth, 1994-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Pierre Deux, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Plume, Charles Eagle, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Purdy, James, Archival Resource Key (Box 42)
    - Correspondence, 1985-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 42, Folder 9-10)
    - Typescript Drafts, 1988-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 42, Folder 11-12)
    - Printed Material on Readings, 1987-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - News Clippings, 1987-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 42, Folder 14)
    - Programs and Announcements for 'Til the Eagle Hollers, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 42, Folder 15)
    - Books Inscribed by Author, 1976-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 42, Folder 16-19)
  - Rauschenberg, Robert, 1966-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 42, Folder 20)
  - Smith, Kiki, 1990-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 42, Folder 21)
  - Smith, Kiki, 1990-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Smith, Seton, 1990-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Smith, Tony, 1997-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Snyder, Scotty, 1990-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Starr, Nina Howell, 1983-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Takaezu, Toshiko, 1970-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 43, Folder 6-7)
  - Teske, Edmund, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Trubek, Katherine Bell, 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Varese, Louise, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Weeks, Stephen Cone, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Youngerman, Jack, 1972-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Calder, copy 1, circa 1976; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel Super 8mm (Item FC 88)
  - Calder, copy 2, circa 1976; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel Super 8mm (Item FC 89)
- Major Film Projects, 1904-2007; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 18.8 Linear feet Boxes 43-61, 81-82, FC 90-91, OV 87; 0.34 Gigabytes ER01
  Major film project files document Maryette Charlton's films about or with artists Frederick Kiesler (Trienniale, The Universal Theater and Kiesler on Kieseler), Lenore Tawney, Dorothy Miller, Loren MacIver, and Jeanne Reynal. The files for Frederick Kiesler also contain materials about his wife Lillian Kiesler, with whom Charlton had a long relationship and collaborated with on film projects. Individual film project files contain a wide variety of research and production documentation, including correspondence, writings, printed material, research files, exhibition catalogs, photographic materials, sound recordings of interviews and lectures, and Charlton's documentation about the creation and producation of each film, such as contracts, scripts, and distribution information. Sound and video recordings are found throughout the series, as well as 2 film reels.
  This series is arranged as 5 subseries.
  8.1: Frederick and Lillian Kiesler, 1938-2004
  8.2: Lenore Tawney, 1943-2007
  8.3: Dorothy Miller, 1904-1994
  8.4: Loren MacIver, 1938-1998
  8.5: Jeanne Reynal, 1961-1983
  - Frederick and Lillian Kiesler, 1938-2004; 8.1; Archival Resource Key
    This subseries consists of material on architect and sculptor Frederick Kiesler and his wife Lillian. There are files on Charlton's films on Frederick Kiesler including Trienniale,The Universal Theater, and Kiesler on Kiesler. Also included are files on the Austrian Kiesler Foundation, transcripts and recordings of lectures and interviews about Kiesler, printed material, correspondence, photographs, writings by and about Kiesler, and performances about Kiesler, including one by Alfred Barr. Sound and video recordings of Frederick and Lillian Kiesler include 35 sound tape reels, 18 sound cassettes, 9 videocassettes, 1 film reel, and 1 digitized sound disc. There are also photographs of Lillian Kiesler in the photographic materials series.
    This subseries is arranged into 3 folder groupings of material on the Austrian Frederick and Lillian Kiesler Foundation, material on Frederick Kiesler, and material on Lillian Kiesler. Folders within each category are grouped together by document type, then arranged chronologically.
    - Austrian Frederick and Lillian Kiesler Foundation, Archival Resource Key (Box 43)
      - Correspondence, 2001-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 43, Folder 13)
      - Exhibitions, 2000-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 43, Folder 14-16)
      - Cedric Price Catalogs, 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 43, Folder 17)
      - WNYC Interview with Maryette Charlton and Lillian Kiesler, 2002; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 43, Folder 18)
    - Frederick Kiesler, Archival Resource Key (Box 43)
      - Biographical Material, 1965-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 43, Folder 19)
      - Kiesler Cemetery Plot A133, 1973-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 43, Folder 20)
      - List of Film Footage on Frederick Kiesler, 1974-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 43, Folder 21)
      - Hirshhorn Museum Film & Lecture Series, 1975-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 43, Folder 22)
      - Whitney Museum Art Donation, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 43, Folder 23)
      - Estate Papers, 1996-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 43, Folder 24)
      - Kiesler Estate Art Inventory, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 43, Folder 25)
      - "Wonder of Being Alive" Art Loan to Hunter College, 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 43, Folder 26)
      - Correspondence about Frederick Kiesler, 1962-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 43, Folder 27)
    - Frederick Kiesler, Archival Resource Key (Box 44)
      - Correspondence about Frederick Kiesler, 1986-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 44, Folder 1-2)
      - Channel 13 Correspondence, 1987-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 44, Folder 3)
      - "Kiesler on Kiesler" Budget Estimates, 1965-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 44, Folder 4)
      - "Kiesler on Kiesler" Shooting Cards, 1966-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 44, Folder 5)
      - "Kiesler on Kiesler" Expenses and Receipts, 1966-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 44, Folder 6)
      - "Kiesler on Kiesler" Preliminary Ideas, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 44, Folder 7)
      - "Kiesler on Kiesler" Requests for Signed Leases, 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 44, Folder 8)
      - "Kiesler on Kiesler" Film Proposal, 1992-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 44, Folder 9)
      - "Kiesler's Studios" Vienna Screening, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 44, Folder 10-11)
      - "Triennale" Final Selections, 1994-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 44, Folder 12)
      - "Universal Theater" Notes, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 44, Folder 13)
      - Working Journal on Filming Kiesler, 1965-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 44, Folder 14)
      - Notecards, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 44, Folder 15)
      - Notes, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 44, Folder 16)
      - Exhibition Catalog Foreword Draft by Thomas Messner, circa 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 44, Folder 17)
      - Typescript Drafts of Tributes and Eulogies, 1960-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 44, Folder 18)
      - Typescript Draft of Obituary by Guenther Feuerstein, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 44, Folder 19)
      - Book Proposal for Frederick Kiesler 1890-1965, 1991-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 44, Folder 20)
      - Finding Aid for Maryette Charlton Research Collection on Frederick Kiesler, 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 44, Folder 21)
      - "Frederick Kiesler's Quest for the 'Ideal House'", 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 44, Folder 22)
      - Progressive Architecture, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 44, Folder 23)
      - Show Magazine, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 44, Folder 24)
        Oversized magazine housed in Box 81
      - Inside the Endless House, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 44, Folder 25)
      - Vogue Magazine, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 44, Folder 26)
      - Friedrich Kiesler: Architekt, Maler, Bildhauer, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 44, Folder 27)
    - Frederick Kiesler, Archival Resource Key (Box 45)
      - Frederick Kiesler: Arte, Architettura, Ambiente, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Frederick Kiesler, Artiste-architecte, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Frederick J. Kiesler: Selected Writings, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 45, Folder 3)
      - Machinations, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 45, Folder 4)
      - Cahier No. 6, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 45, Folder 5)
      - Frederick Kiesler 1890-1965, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 45, Folder 6)
        Oversized book housed in Box 81
      - Friedrich Kiesler: Inside the Endless House, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 45, Folder 7)
      - Articles by Frederick Kiesler, circa 1957-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 45, Folder 8)
      - German Exhibition Catalog, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 45, Folder 9)
      - "An Evening Dedicated to F. Kiesler" Event Program, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 45, Folder 10)
      - Das Archiv Des Visionars Poster, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 45, Folder 11)
        Oversized poster housed in OV 87
      - Clippings about "Us, You, Me" Parrish Museum Installation, 2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 45, Folder 12)
      - Hunter College - Moved Exhibition (2004), Archival Resource Key (Box 45, Folder 13)
      - Printed Material, 1964-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 45, Folder 14-15)
      - Photographs of Frederick Kiesler, 1963-circa 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 45, Folder 16-17)